Objective

My goals are delivering a timely quality product, focus on expanding my skills to meet future needs, and finding a roll that challenges my growth as a software engineer. I have experience in Java/Kotlin/Groovy SpringBoot, REST, Python, JS, Agile, DevOps, algorithms, & design patterns. I am a mindful team player, and communicator with a passion for knowledge sharing and mentorship.

Skills

Languages: Java, Kotlin, C#, JavaScript, Groovy, Python, SQL

Technologies:

Java/Kotlin/Groovy - AWS SDK 2v, Spring/SpringBoot, SpringWeb, SpringMVC, SpringCloudDiscovery, SpringSecurity, ThymeLeaf, Hibernate, HATEOAS, Junit, Mockito, PowerMock, REST, SOA, Microservices, postgresSQL, MariaDB, mySQL, MAMP, MongoDB, TDD, BDD, NoSQL, Event Streaming, TestNG

C# - FrameWork, .Net Core, XUnit, Telerik JustMock, TDD

Python - Flask, SQLAlchemy, Jinja2, Redis

JavaScript - NPM, React, Redux, TypeScript

DevOps CICD - Shared Pipeline Library (Groovy), Scripted Pipeline, Declarative Pipeline, Infrastructure as Code, Jenkins, Cloud Bees Core, Blue Ocean, Artifactory, Ansible, SonarQube, Selenium, SauceLabs, Azure Devops, Terraform, Github Actions

Developer Tools - Agile, IntelliJ, Eclipse, PyCharm, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, MAMP, Maven, Gradle, Anaconda, Jira, Git, GitFlow, Github Enterprise, Postman

Experience



SOFTWARE ENGINEER, AGENTSYNC, DENVER, CO - 2022 - 2023

Notable Projects:

Insurance contracting platform - Java | SpringBoot | Hibernate | HATEOAS | SQL, React | Typescript | Redux | AWS

- Developed greenfield customer facing full stack applications
- Tech lead on medium size features- AWS Disaster Recovery, various tech debt, and workflows
- Provided technical and career mentorship within the company



SOFTWARE ENGINEER II, PAX8, DENVER, CO - 2021 - 2022

Notable Projects:

E-commerce Platform - Kotlin | Java | Groovy | SpringBoot | PostgresSQL | Vue | AWS | NoSQL

- Maintained and expanded features across domains of e-commerce platform. Worked with SMEs to maintain pace as individual contributor across domains. Produced weekly regression fixes.
- Worked in micro service and monolith architectures Book Club
- Participated in weekly book club readings and discussions continuing personal and team growth



 ${\bf SOFTWARE\ DEVELOPER,\ VETERANS\ UNITED\ HOME\ LOAN,\ ST\ LOUIS,\ MO-2020-2021}$

Notable Projects:

Loan Origination Plugins and Services - C#

• Maintained and expanded features of plugin suite & SOAP services for Loan Origination

- Introduce TDD into legacy codebase, decouple code using best practices & eliminate anti patterns
- Migrated source control from TFVC to Git

Source Control Guild - TFVC | Git

• Participated weekly to modernize source control facilitating Devops & XP culture



ASSOCIATE PROGRAMMER ANALYST, EXPRESS SCRIPTS, ST LOUIS, MO – 2018-2020

Notable Projects:

QA Testing Framework - Java | SpringBoot | Pivotal Cloud Foundry | NoSQL

- Maintained and built upon Java/Spring REST app/QA framework used for company wide e2e testing
- Built MVP Spring Cloud Load-balancer for balancing traffic between multiple Docker Swarms of Selenium Grid containers, and other containerized micro-services.
- Maintained JavaScript/Node/MongoDB-NoSQL Service used for End to End coverage Micro Service Migration - Java | SpringBoot | Pivotal Cloud Foundry
- Remove individual entities from Java monolith, wrap entities in new Java SpringBoot application Shared Pipeline Library - Groovy | Jenkins
- Modularize shared library and creation of 2.0v shared library for Jenkins/Cloud Bees Core
- Increased Shared Pipeline code test coverage from 10% to 54% utilizing Spock Framework
- Assisted in 50+ teams getting automated build to production through guidance, training, & pairing



CONTRACTOR, EXPRESS SCRIPTS, ST LOUIS, MO -2018 -2018

Notable Projects:

Regression Testing Application - Python | Flask | Jinja | Html | css

- Build Python/Flask MVC web app upon existing command line app increasing tester adoption
- Expand coverage from 3 MITRE ATTA&CK MATRIX strategies to 56 strategies



LEAD INSTRUCTOR, LAUNCHCODE, ST LOUIS, MO - 2018 - 2018

Responsibilities:

- Taught lecture-stye classroom of 150 students Object-Oriented Programing & MVC in Python
- Produced and delivered slide lectures on OOP geared towards best practices and clean code
- Coordinated 12 Teaching assistants on curriculum and students progress to ensure student retention



TEACHING ASSISTANT, LAUNCHCODE, ST LOUIS, MO - 2018 - 2020

Responsibilities:

- Lead lab group of 15 students facilitating technical growth, & communication growth
- Host daily lab exercises teaching Java, SpringBoot, CRUD, MVC & JavaScript, npm
- 1:1 instruction with students reinforcing assignments Java & JS tech stacks

EDUCATION

LaunchCode, St Louis, MO – Certificate, CS - 2017 - Bootcamp intro to CS & Web Development foundational Java/SpringBoot MVC CRUD applications, SQL, OOP, & python University of Nebraska Lincoln 3.5gpa, Lincoln, NE – Master of Fine Arts, Sculpture - 2013 Southern Illinois University Edwardsville, Edwardsville, IL – Bachelor of Fine Arts, Sculpture - 2008